[Music]
for this tutorial you will need your
selected yarn I'm using stylecraft
special DK in aspin and spring green you
will also need a crochet hook I'm using
a 5 mm you'll need a pair of scissors
and a darling needle to begin your
project we're going to start by making a
chain so first of all you want to create
your slip
knot
and insert your
hook we're going to start with a
foundation chain and this Foundation
chain needs to be in multiples of six
I'm going to chain
24 but you can chain however much you
need in order to get the width of the
blanket or whatever project you're
working on so you want to yarn over pull
through yarn over pull
through yarn over pull through yarn over
pull through yarn over pull through yarn
over pull through so that is six
stitches I'm going to go ahead and chain
a few more till I reach 24 um if you
want to pause the video here and come
back when you've got your selected
length so I've now chained my length of
24 stitches and what you want to do is
when you've got the length you want you
then want to do an
additional chain two so chain two more
and this will be for
turning so we're now going to go back
along this chain in inserting our first
row of shell Stitch so we're going to
skip this chain here and then work into
the second chain from the hook and we're
going to do a double crochet in here so
this would be called single crochet in
the US so all you want to do is insert
your
hook yarn over
pull
through yarn over pull through the other
two loops on your
hook we then want to skip two chains so
we're skipping this one and this one and
we're working into the third
chain and we're now going to do a treble
crochet and this is called double
crochet in the US so we want to yarn
over remember we're skipping the next
two chains and in inserting it into the
third
one so insert your hook yarn over pull
through yarn over pull through
two yarn over pull through two so that
is one treble crochet or double crochet
if you're in the US we're then going to
do four more so there's going to be five
triple crochets in this
space so we'll do our second one
third
fourth and
fifth
so that's now five trible crochets in
that one stitch we're then going to skip
two chains again so one two and then do
a double crochet in this third chain so
the hook goes straight
in yarn over pull
through yarn over pull through to the
two two loops on the hook so now that is
your first shell shape then going to go
straight into the next Shell so all we
do is simply skip two again and we're
going to do five trebles into the third
chain along so yarn
over
insert yarn over pull through yarn over
pull through two yarn over pull through
through two and then you're going to do
four
more so that is
three four
and five so that is our second shell we
now just need to attach it to the chain
so we skip two spaces and then do
one double crochet into the third chain
so Skip Skip and then into here so we go
straight
into the chain yarn over pull through
yarn over and pull through two and we're
simply going to repeat this all the way
to the end so if you want to pause the
video here I'll leave the instructions
below and I shall meet you back at the
end of this
row okay so I'm now at the end of my row
and because I chained 24 I end up with
four shell stitches that's because one
set one multiple of six equals one shell
so at the end you will be left with
three chains and you want to just insert
your hook into the very last
chain yarn over pull through yarn over
pull through two now I'm going to change
colors at this point so that I've got um
each row as a different color but if you
wanted to keep the same color you can
just chain one at this point I'm
actually just going to tie off so I'm
just going to yarn over pull the yarn
through cut
off take out the yarn and pull nice and
tight and this is the way I always
change colors just because I feel that
it's a lot more sturdy this way but I
realized it's not the technically
correct way to do it so that section
there where I've just um tied off my
yarn I'm going to insert my
hook into the the space of the last
Chain Grab my new
color and pull
through and then tie
off and then grab my hook again sit into
the same
space and yarn
over and pull through so we now at the
same point as what we were uh with the
other color so all you want to do now is
chain one and then turn your
work and we're going to do a half shell
in this same space so you want to yarn
over
insert yarn over pull
through yarn over pull through two and
yarn over pull through two so that's one
treble and we're going to do two more
trebles so that's
two and that's three so that's our half
shell we then want to skip two chain
spaces so this is one this is two and
this is our third one which we're going
to work in so you want to insert your
hook into that space and you're working
into the top of the space so when you
put your um hook in it should look like
you have like a little V on here or two
two Loops you want to insert your hook
yarn over pull through and yarn over
pull through two that makes the dip of
our
shell we're then going to skip the next
two spaces so one two and then then the
third space if you just pull it apart
cuz this this Stitch might be a bit
tighter uh but this is the Stitch that
we're going to be working in and we're
going to do our five trebles in that
Stitch so it's yarn
over
insert and again it will look like it's
got two loops on the hook yarn over pull
through yarn over pull through two yarn
over pull through two so that's our
first treble now going to do
four more in that
space so
one
two
and four we now need to attach this end
so we're going to skip two spaces and
insert our hook into the third
space yarn over pull through yarn over
pull
through so this is how it should be
looking at the
moment we have our full shells down at
the bottom we have a half shell at the
beginning
and then we have a full shell here we've
just done our double crochet in this
Stitch and you want to skip two and do
five trebles into this third Stitch here
pause the video and work your way all
the way along and I shall meet you at
the end and I'll show you how to do the
third row so now I'm at the end of this
row to the point where I've just done a
double crochet into this last shell
we're then going to miss two stitches
and work our three treble crochets into
this third Stitch along which is the
very last Stitch of the row so yarn
over
insert yarn over pull through yarn over
pull through two yarn over pull through
two and you just want to do two more of
those
and to finish off this row you want
to insert your hook yarn over pull
through yarn over pull
through if you're staying with the same
color you would just chain one at this
point but I'm going to yarn over pull
through and cut off
my
YN pull through and then get ready to
change color again so I'm back with my
um Aspen color and I'm going to insert
my hook into this space here grab the
yarn pull
through and then tie
off insert my hook into that same space
again and yarn over and pull through so
you now want to chain one and turn your
work and we are going to be working
into this dip section
here so I actually have um three chains
before I get to this one here so it
depends where you've inserted your yarn
into if you've got three it doesn't
really matter we can just work into this
this one here so it's the the bit that
attaches down into your previous row so
you want to yarn over insert your hook
into that Stitch yarn over pull through
yarn over pull through two yarn over
pull through two and you're going to do
um five trebles in total into that
section so you want to go ahead and do
four more treble
crochets into that same chain
space so it's
one
two
3 and
four we're going to skip two chains and
then do a double into the top of this
shell skip two and then five trebles
into this
bottom chain here the third
chain
along so I'm going to go ahead and work
my way to the end of this row again so
if you want to pause the video meet me
back at the end and I shall explain what
to do
next so now I'm at the end of this row
and all I'm going to do is skip two
chains I've just done my five trebles
here so Skip One skip two and insert the
hook into the third chain
along and I'm going to do a double
crochet in there I'm going to yarn over
pull
through snip off my
yarn and then I will go ahead and attach
my uh light green color again now this
is just a two row repeat so our next row
and this will be the same whenever using
this light green color is that I would
do the half shell which consists of
three treble um at the beginning and of
the end of the row and exactly the same
pattern as you've been working through
so you can make this as big or as small
as you want you could also use different
colors on each row uh but it's a really
pretty pattern and it's quite simple and
easy to do once you get the hang of it I
really hope you've enjoyed this tutorial
I would love to see your projects so
make sure you tag me on Instagram or
Twitter using # Bell Coco and my
username at Bell
Coco please make sure you thumbs up if
you like this video And subscribe to see
more tutorials thank you very much for
watching see you again next time
[Music]
bye